Can you help me pick an engagement ring?
菲比，幫我挑訂婚戒指好嗎？
I can't figure this out. Should I get her a Tiffany cut or a princess cut or a..?
我覺得好難挑喔 我要選第凡內切割法還是… 公主方切割法還是…
Paper cut!
紙張切割法
-Have you told anyone else? -No,I don't want Monica to find out.
你有告訴其他人嗎？ 沒有，我不想讓摩妮卡發現
You told me.
可是你告訴我了
Because I trust you and we're friends...
因為我信任你 你是我的死黨之一
and you saw me looking at ring brochures.
而且你在我看型錄時闖進來
Once again, not knocking pays off.
進房不敲門再次大有斬獲
-I wish you hadn't been on the toilet. -Me too.
如果你不是在蹲馬桶就好了 我有同感
Let me see. Is there such a thing as a Monica cut?
我看看，有摩妮卡切割法嗎？
Because that would be you best bet.
有的話就是它了
-Want to go to the coffeehouse? -Oh,all right.
錢德，要不要去喝咖啡？ 好啊 走吧
We were just gonna see if you wanted to go.
太好了，我們正想找你們下去
Well,we don't because we got the other place.
不要，我們要去別家
How rude.
真沒禮貌
Sorry. Want a bite?
抱歉，你要吃嗎？
The One With The Ring
本集播出：「完美的戒指」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
So how are things going with Paul?
你和保羅交往得怎樣？
Good.
很好
Although,you know, he's a private guy.
只不過他很內斂
I wish I could get him to open up, share some feelings.
真想讓他稍微敞開心胸 分享心情
You just have to think of him as a jar of pickles that won't open.
簡單 把他想成打不開的罐子就對了
I should run him under hot water and bang his head against a table?
你要我捉他的頭沖熱水敲桌子
That's what you do when you want to get the truth out of someone.
不是，那是拷問的手法
-Watch this. -Okay.
看我的 好
-Hey,Paul. -Hi,Phoebe.
-保羅  -菲比
How are things going with you?
你最近好嗎？
Can't complain.
沒得抱怨
Let's go！
走吧
-Great to.. -Ross,good to see you too.
-很高興...  -我也很高興見到你
You take care.
保重
What was the deal with you and Chandler blowing us off before?
你們剛才為什麼見到我們就跑
That was so weird,huh?
很怪吧？
Why did you do it?
菲比，為什麼？
I didn't do it. It was Chandler.
不是我，是錢德
He's mad at you.
他…他在生你們的氣
-What? Why? -Oh,please. I think you know why.
-什麼？ 為什麼？ -拜託，你明知故問
I can't think of anything.
我想不起來
Come on. You're a paleontologist. Dig a little deeper.
羅斯，你是古生物學家 再往下挖
Is it because Joey and I didn't invite him to that Knicks game?
等等，是不是因為兩個星期前 喬伊和我沒找他去看球？
Is that something he'd be mad at you for?
你覺得他會為這種事生氣嗎？
-I guess it could. -Well,then I think that's it.
應該會 那就是羅
If he's angry, he shouldn't hide it. I wish he'd just tell me the truth.
他不該隱瞞他的情緒 他應該老實告訴我
You should run him under hot water and bang his head against the table.
那你應該捉他的頭 去沖熱水敲桌子
Honey,I made a reservation at China Garden. Is that okay?
我在「中國花園」訂了位 可以嗎？
Yeah,that's great.
可以啊，很棒
But first,talk to me. Talk to me. Tell me about your day.
但你先跟我說說話 說說你今天好不好
It was fine.
蠻好的
Okay.
好吧
What are you thinking right now?
你在想什麼？你現在在想什麼
That you are looking really fine in that dress.
我在想你穿這件裙子很好看
Yeah, that's great, Paul. But, you know....
太好了，但是…
I want to know what.. Wow, those are really great!
我想知道…哇，好結實
I just want to know...
我想知道...
what is behind this strong, silent exterior?
這堅強沉默的外表下 隱藏著什麼
They say that still waters run deep, and I want to swim in yours.
俗語說靜水深流 我想在你的心中暢遊
Are you talking about having sex?
你在講做愛的事嗎？
No, Paul.
不是
I don't know anything about you. Tell me about your childhood.
我一點也不瞭解你 例如你的童年，聊聊你的童年
Normal.
很普通
Then how about puberty? Come on! That's always a painful time.
好，那青春期呢？ 青春期總是很討厭
Your friends have a slumber party and stick your hand in warm water...
朋友找你去過夜聊天 趁你睡著把你的手放進熱水裡
while you sleep, so you pee in your sleeping bag.
害你在睡袋裡撒尿
No,that never happened to me.
我沒碰過那種事
You're lucky you never met that bitch, Sharon Majeski.
那是你走運 沒碰上那個賤人莎朗麥傑斯基
Anyway...
總之…
The rest of your life. Any regrets?
其他時期有什麼悔恨嗎？
Nope.
沒有
I'm not asking for a lot here.
保羅，我要求得不多
Just give me something. Anything.
你就講一件事，什麼事都好
-Okay. -Okay.
好吧
When I was 6 years old, I wanted a Big Wheel.
6歲那年 我想要一輛大腳踏車
And instead,my parents got me this little...
我父母卻送我一個...
plastic chicken that you hop around on.
小雞造型的跳跳樂
It was embarrassing. Kids made fun of me.
糗死了，小朋友都笑我
That was a tough year.
那一年蠻痛苦的
That's great! See?
太好了，你看吧
I already feel like I know you a little better.
我覺得我比較瞭解你了，謝謝
Okay,come on. Now we can go eat. Let's go!
好，我們去吃飯吧
It was horrible.
我好慘
They called me "Chicken Boy."
大家都叫我雞弟弟
In fifth grade,I got in a fight. Well, not really.
五年級我跟別人打架 其實也不算打架
Richard Danville bit me.
理查達倫咬我的鼻子
I still have a little scar right here. You can see it.
我摔倒 這裡留了一個小疤
Yeah,yeah. I see the scar.
有，我看見了
I think this is really great that, you know, you've shared your feelings.
保羅，你聽我說 你這樣分享你的心情真的很棒
It's really... It's beautiful.
真的很..好
But what do you say we go share some food?
那我們現在去吃飯吧
No,I couldn't eat now.
我現在吃不下
What are you talking about? You love their Kung Pao chicken!
你在說什麼？ 你最愛吃宮保雞丁了
Chicken?
雞？
-Chicken Boy! -I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
雞弟弟 天哪，對不起，我不是故意的
This is the nine millionth ring store, and I can't find the perfect ring.
一無所獲 逛了幾百家店 還是找不到完美的戒指
Ugly ring, ugly ring, ugly ring...
丑，丑，丑
It's a beautiful selection.
這些戒指真美
So maybe you don't get her a ring. Maybe you do something different.
不然你不要送戒指 送點不一樣的
An engagement bracelet or an engagement tiara!
例如訂婚手鐲，或是訂婚頭飾
An engagement Revolutionary War musket!
訂婚獨立戰爭毛瑟槍
I'm so glad I picked you to help me with this.
真高興我是選你來幫忙
Imagine getting down on one knee...
你能不能想像你單膝跪下
and handing her this gorgeous piece of weaponry?
把這件漂亮的火器交給她？
I'll stick with the ring.
我還是送戒指好了
This one's nice. I like it. Sir?
這只好漂亮，我喜歡這只
Kind sir, can I see this one?
先生？大哥？我想看這枚戒指
This is why you brought me. I know how to haggle.
你找我來就是因為我會講價
-Let me handle this from here. -Can I help you?
所以接下來交給我處理  有什麼需要嗎？
-I would like to see that ring. -Or not. Whatever.
有，我想看那枚戒指 或是不看，隨便
This ring is from the 1920s.
這是一隻20年代的戒指
It's a one and a half carat diamond with sapphires.
1.5克拉，兩側鑲有藍寶石
Sir, could I ask you...?
先生，你能不能…
Could you hold out that ring and ask me to marry you?
拿著戒指向我求婚？
-Okay. -Okay.
好
Will you marry me?
你願意嫁給我嗎？
Oh, my God, that's it! That's the ring!
天哪，就是它了
-How much is it? -I will handle this.
-多少錢？ -錢德，讓我來
How much is it?
多少錢？
$8600.
8千6
We will give you $10.
我們出10塊錢
-Are you interested in this ring? -Yes.
-你到底想不想買？ -想，想
But I can only pay $8000.
但我只能出8千
-Okay. I can let it go for 8. -We stand firm at $10.
-好，8千可以 -我們堅持10塊錢
-How would you like to pay? -Credit card.
您要怎麼付帳？ --刷卡
Oh,no! I lent my credit card to Joey.
不對，我的卡在喬伊那邊
I'll go get it. You guard the ring.
我回去拿，你守住戒指
-Why did you give your credit card to Joey? -To buy some Knicks tickets.
-你為什麼把你的卡給喬伊？ -他要買尼克隊的球票
Then the jerk didn't even invite me to the game. But I'm over it. Whatever!
結果他居然沒有找我一起去  不過我已經不在意了
Listen, I'm sorry about before.
剛才很抱歉
Do you have anything here for $10?
你們有10塊錢的東西嗎？
Yes. I have these two rather beautiful...
有，我有兩張嶄新的...
five-dollar bills.
5元鈔票
I'll give you $1 for them.
我出1塊錢跟你買
Remember how Chandler and Phoebe blew us off yesterday?
昨天錢德和菲比 不是看到我們就跑？
No.
有嗎？
-Remember,you were eating pizza? -Yeah.
你當時在吃披薩 喔對
Chandler's angry at us for not getting him a ticket to that Knicks game.
錢德顯然是在氣我們2星期前 沒幫他買球票
We were supposed to just get him one? That guy's always mooching off of us.
我們為什麼要幫他買票？ 那傢伙老是揩我們的油 就是啊
Anyway,I still think we should try to patch things up.
但我還是覺得應該設法和解
We could get tickets to another game and invite him.
我們可以找他去看另一場球賽
That's a great idea. And I still have his credit card.
好主意 而且他的卡還在我這裡
Here you go.
帳單
Hey,hey. I got this one. Here you go.
我有卡，拿去吧
Sometimes I just don't get Chandler.
有時候我真搞不懂錢德
We do stuff all the time without you, and you don't get all upset.
我和他做很多事都沒找你 你也不會生氣
-All the time? -All the time.
很多事？ 可多了
I'm sorry,it was rejected.
抱歉，這張卡不能刷
That's impossible. Let me see that.
不可能，我看看
This one's mine. Here you go.
這張是我的，拿去吧
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
我的天哪  我的天哪
-Still crying? -Like a little girl.
還在哭？ 跟小女生一樣
I know,I know. This is all my fault.
我知道…都是我不好
I wanted him to open up.
是我要他敞開心胸的
I didn't know that I was gonna unleash...
但是我不知道我會放出一頭...
this weepy,clingy, moist monster!
哭哭啼啼又黏人的怪物
I only know of two ways to shut a man up. One of them is sex.
有兩個辦法能讓一個男人閉嘴 其中一個是性愛
-What's the other? -Don't know. Never had to use it.
-另一個是什麼？ -不知道，我只用過第一個
I'm just saying, if we're having sex, he's not talking.
我只是說做愛的時候 他就不能講話
That's right. You're the talker.
沒錯，話多的是你
Anyway, great idea.
總之這個主意很棒
I gotta buy him some more tissues.
我要去商店 我答應去幫他買面紙
-We have some here. -No,you don't!
-我們這裡有… -你們沒有
Okay. I'd also like to try on the tiara.
好，我還想試戴頭飾
Oh,yeah. Okay.
太好了
What do you think? Too much?
怎麼樣？太花了？
A tad.
有一點
Take the tiara back...
把頭飾放回去
and let me hold the musket again.
毛瑟槍再給我一次
Something's missing.
少了點什麼…
Let me see the ring that my friend picked out.
把我朋友挑的戒指拿給我
-Where's the 1920s princess-cut ring? -I just sold it to that gentleman.
-那枚20年代的鑽戒呢？ -剛剛賣給那位先生
Oh,my God!
完蛋了
Wait,no!
等等，別走
Let me out! Now!
放我出去，快點
Rachel?
瑞秋…
No.
不是
-How are you, Paul? -Okay.
保羅，你好嗎？ 還好
Chandler...
錢德…
-did your dad ever hug you? -No. Did he hug you?
-你爸抱過你嗎？  -沒有，他抱過你嗎？
No! No.
不是
It's just that my dad never did.
只不過我爸都沒抱過我
I miss my dad.
我好想念我爸
You can see my dad in Vegas kissing other dads.
你可以去賭城 看我爸親別人的爸爸
-Hey,Chandler? -Yeah?
錢德？ 怎樣？
Would you...?
你能不能…
Would you hug me?
你能不能抱我？
-I'm a little busy here, Paul. -That's what my dad used to say.
-我有點忙  -我爸也都這麼說
Okay. A quick one. Come on, hug it out.
好啦，一下下，快點
There you go.
行了吧
Okay.
好了
-Five more seconds.. -Okay!
-再5秒鐘 -夠了
-Joey! -What? Hey, what..?
-喬伊  -什麼？
Hi. Paul,is it?
保羅是吧？
-Do you have my credit card? -Yeah. It's in my...
我的信用卡在嗎？ 在，在我的…
In my pocket.
我的口袋裡
-My back pocket! -Thank God.
-後面的口袋 -幸好
-I got tickets to the Knicks tonight. -I can't go.
-我買了今天晚上尼克隊的票 -我不能去
It'll be fun.
去啦，多好玩啊
Me, you, Ross and Paul, probably.
我，你，羅斯和… 保羅嗎？
Look, I don't have time for this, okay? I gotta go.
我沒空好嗎，我得走了
That was mean.
好惡劣喔
Yeah,I know.
就是啊
-Get in here. -Yeah.
過來吧 好
Chandler, I found the perfect ring.
錢德，我找到最完美的戒指了
I'm gonna go with the one I picked first.
真不錯 但我還是買之前那款好了
Oh, wake up. The one you picked is gone. It's over!
天哪，錢德，那枚戒指不在了
What?
什麼？
Some guy bought it. I tried to stop him, but they put me in jail!
被一個人買走了，對不起 我想攔住他，卻被關進監獄裡
-They put you in jail? -The little jail between the doors!
-被關進監獄裡？ -門和門中間的小監獄
-I asked you to guard the ring! -I know. I'm sorry.
-菲比，我要你守著那枚戒指 -我知道，對不起
But this ring is better. And Monica never saw the other ring.
但是這枚比較好 摩妮卡根本沒看過另一枚
Yeah,but when he proposed to me with the ring, I got goosebumps.
但是他用那枚戒指向我求婚時 我起了雞皮疙瘩
-Maybe it was the guy. -It was the ring!
-也許是因為那個人 -是因為那枚戒指
-Was he excited about the tickets? -No! He blew us off!
-他興奮嗎？ -不，他回絕了
-What? -I know.
什麼？ 就是啊
I can't believe it.
真是太扯了
Can I tell you something?
告訴你
I'm a little mad at him now!
我現在有點氣他
Can I tell you something?
告訴你
Me too!
我也是
He didn't want to talk to us about being angry.
他生氣不告訴我們
Maybe we don't talk to him at all!
那我們也不要告訴他
-Freeze him out. -Right!
-把他打入冷宮  -沒錯
-I like it. -We'll show him.
-我喜歡 -給他好看
From now on,it's gonna be Joey and Ross, best friends.
以後就是喬伊與羅斯 最佳拍檔
We'll be the new Joey and Chandler.
我們將是新的喬伊與錢德
What?
什麼？
You think you and Chandler were closer than me and Chandler?
你覺得你和錢德比我和錢德更好？
Hey, don't get angry.
別生氣
We turn on each other, he wins.
我們一反目，他就贏了
Hi,I'm back.
我回來了
I've written down more to tell you!
我把我想說的話都寫下來了
Oh,that's great.
真好
No,actually,that's...
真是太好了
That's great. That's really great.
真的好棒
You know,I gotta tell you, writing, all that writing, it gets me...
說真的，寫東西會燃起…
It gets me kind of hot.
我的慾火
Wait, wait. Listen to this:
等等，你聽喔
Know what I wanted to be at that age?
你知道我小時候想當什麼？
A lover?
情聖？
-A surfer. -A surfer?
-衝浪者 -是嗎？
-I wanted to be one with the waves.. -Hold on.
-我想與海浪為伍  -等等，等一下
Let me just get a little more comfortable here.
讓我把自己弄得舒服一點
Wait a second.
等一下
-This isn't too revealing,is it? -No.
-這樣會不會太露了？  -不會
Whatever happened to that little dude?
當年那個小傢伙呢？
So full of dreams.
充滿夢想…
I don't care about the little dude!
我不在乎那個小傢伙
I can't! I cannot listen to any more of this!
我聽不下去了
The only one who'd listen is a mental health professional!
只有心理醫師會想聽這些話
That's only because they get $100 an hour!
那還是因為他們1小時賺1百
Do you know how much money I could have made listening to you? $2000!
你知道我聽到現在可以賺多少  2千塊！
Know when I figured that out? While you were talking!
你知道我什麼時候算出來的？ 在你碎碎念的時候
I can't believe you're trying to stifle me when 14 hours ago...
你居然想扼殺我的情緒 14個小時前...
we figured out that's what my mother was trying to do!
我們才發現那就是我媽的目的
I'm sorry.
對不起
I don't mean... I didn't mean to stifle you.
我不是想扼殺你的情緒
This is all just a little overwhelming.
我只是有點受不了
I'm so sorry.
瑞秋，對不起
I didn't mean to overwhelm you.
我不是故意的
It's just that when those gates open...
只不過情緒一發洩
it's hard to close them.
就會…不可收拾
But they are closed now. Believe me.
不過現在沒事了，真的
I'm so glad. I'm so glad you shared.
我很高興你跟我分享你的心情
And I'm glad that you're done.
也很高興你分享完了
So what do you say we....
那我們要不要…
I'd like that.
我求之不得
That was so good!
真是…太棒了
Oh,oh.
I can't believe you talked me into this gumball-machine-looking ring.
我居然聽你的話 買下這枚造型廉價的戒指
It's not a gumball-machine-looking ring. It's a beautiful ring!
它才沒有造型廉價，它很漂亮
No, it's not.
它才不漂亮
When I looked at the other ring, I could see Monica's face...
另一枚戒指 會讓我看到摩妮卡的表情
and I could see her saying yes. Looking at this,I only see a ring.
我會看到她點頭答應 這枚戒指只讓我看到一枚戒指
Unless I look at it really closely, and then I can see my own eye.
只有近看才會看到我自己的眼睛
This is the most important thing I'll ever do. I want to make it perfect.
這是我這輩子最重要的一件事 我想做到最完美
Maybe we could get the other ring back.
我們或許能把那枚戒指要回來
I heard where the guy was gonna propose.
我偷聽到那個人準備求婚的地方
-Maybe we could get him to trade rings. -I can't do that.
-或許我們可以說服他交換  -我不能這麼做
You certainly can't give her that stupid gumball ring.
你總不能給她那枚廉價的戒指
-All right. Where was he going? -Yeah,it's a restaurant...
-好吧，他要去哪裡？ -一家餐廳…
-The Rainbow something. -Rainbow Room? -No.
-彩虹什麼的  -彩虹餐廳？ -不是
-Rainbow Grill? -No.
-彩虹燒烤？ -不是
Somewhere Over the...?
彩虹的彼端？（電影「綠野仙蹤」主題曲）
-L'Espace. -Rainbow L'Espace!
-空間  -彩虹空間？
No,just L'Espace.
不是，只有空間
I'd love to know how you got from rainbow to L'Espace.
你是怎麼從彩虹跳到空間的
No, you wouldn't.
你不會想知道的
You don't wanna get in here.
我的思路很複雜
There he is.
就是他
He hasn't proposed yet. She has no ring on.
好，他還沒求婚 因為她沒有戴戒指
Wow, you're good! After this, we should solve crimes.
你真行，我們應該去當偵探
Okay. Go get him.
沒錯 去請他過來
Oh,okay.
好
Excuse me. Could you come with me? You have a phone call.
抱歉，請您來一下 有您的電話
-Who is it? -It's your office.
是誰？ 是你的公司打來的
-Do you know who at my office? -John.
-你知道是誰嗎？ -約翰？
Oh,John! Great!
約翰啊，太好了
-There he is. -Hi. Okay.
-他來了 -你好
There was a mix-up at the store.
珠寶店搞錯了
The ring you have was supposed to be held for me.
他們把為我保留的戒指賣給你
I'm gonna need to have that back.
所以我得跟你要回來
In exchange, I'm willing to trade you this beautiful, more expensive ring.
不過我願意拿這枚美麗的 更昂貴的戒指和你交換
Wow, I would trade.
要是我就換
It is beautiful, but I'm gonna use this one. Excuse me.
的確很美，但是我要用這一枚 失陪了
This is my fiancee, and her heart was set on that ring.
不，這位是我的未婚妻 她就是要這枚戒指
Do you want to break her heart?
你不會想傷她的心吧？
Yeah. Do you want to break a dying woman's heart?
對啊 你想傷一位垂死女人的心嗎？
You're dying?
你要死了？
Yeah,she's dying...
她快死於…
of a cough,apparently.
咳嗽了
It's my dying wish to have that ring. If I'm not buried with it...
對，我臨死前想擁有那枚戒指 要是不能戴著它入土
my spirit will wander the netherworld..
我會變成孤魂野鬼在陰間…
That's enough!
夠了，親愛的
Oh,I don't know.
我不曉得
-Let me see it. -Great. Okay, here.
-再讓我看一次  -當然，請看
-All right,I'll do it. -Thank you.
-好吧  -謝謝，謝謝，謝謝
And you are about to marry a wonderful man.
你即將嫁給一個大好人
Hey, I'm marrying a dead woman!
我要娶一個死人
Guys?
兄弟們？
I've got something important to tell you.
我有大事要宣佈
Guys?
兄弟們？
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我要跟摩妮卡求婚了
I think we gotta end the freeze-out.
我們應該讓他從冷宮出來
Wait. Is this for real?
等等，你是來真的？
Yeah. Check out the ring.
對，戒指在這裡
Oh,my God!
天哪
So you two are really serious?
你們真的是認真的？
Yeah, pretty much.
差不多
You're gonna get married?
你們要結婚了？
We're gonna be brothers-in-law! Come here!
我們要成為連襟了，過來
And we're gonna be friends again.
我們又可以當朋友了
What?
什麼？
-Water under the bridge! Forget it! -Okay.
-過去的事就別提了 -好吧
I was gonna wait till it was official, but I had to tell you guys.
我本來想等搞定再說 但我還是忍不住要告訴你們
You're my best friends.
因為你們是我的死黨
-I can't believe this. -Me too.
-我真不敢相信  -我也是
I was planning on having a conversation with you about your intentions.
我本來還想問你有什麼打算
I think I'm gonna cry.
我要哭了
Oh! No more crying!
別再哭了，拜託
I just dumped one crybaby. I'll dump you too.
我剛甩掉一個愛哭寶寶 小心我也甩了你
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我要跟摩妮卡求婚
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Oh,Chandler! You guys are gonna be so happy!
錢德，你們會好幸福
-I know. -Where's all the tissues?!
-我知道  -面紙都死哪去了？
-Check out the ring. -Oh, nice. One and a half carat, easy.
-這是戒指  -真好，至少有1.5克拉
-Hey. -Hey,Phoebe.
菲比
-He's gonna ask Monica to marry him. -Oh, I know. I helped pick out the ring.
-錢德要跟摩妮卡求婚了 -我知道，是我陪他去挑戒指的
You told her before you told us?
你先告訴她？
She walked in while I was looking at brochures. You can understand that.
我在看戒指型錄時被她撞見 你們能諒解吧？
Guys?
兄弟們？
God, that ring Chandler picked out was so beautiful.
天哪，錢德選的戒指好美
You should know. You've bought like a billion of them.
你當然識貨，你買過一大堆
Humor based on my pain.
拿我的痛處開玩笑
You know what's funny?
有趣的是
Of all of your wives, I'm the only one who never got a ring.
你的老婆裡只有我沒拿到戒指
This a big issue for you?
你很在意嗎？
No, but it would have been nice to have a little memento...
不是，只不過如果能有紀念品
of our married time together.
總是蠻好的
Something other than the divorce papers and the hangover.
而不要只有離婚證書和宿醉
Ross is obviously not gonna get you a ring.
羅斯顯然不會送你戒指
But ask for a musket. Ask for a musket!
不過跟他要毛瑟槍
When we were married, do you know what I never got?
你知道我們結婚時 少做了什麼事？
Sex.
上床
Well,yeah. No ring,no sex. Big surprise.
沒戒指當然沒得做，你還敢提
Get me a musket and we'll talk.
送我毛瑟槍，一切好談